<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Portfolio website for Brendan Kermorvan</title>
    <link>https://brendk.netlify.app/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Portfolio website for Brendan Kermorvan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 22:27:21 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://brendk.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello R Markdown</title>
      <link>https://brendk.netlify.app/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brendk.netlify.app/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>R MarkdownThis is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com.
You can embed an R code chunk like this:
summary(cars)## speed dist ## Min. : 4.0 Min. : 2.00 ## 1st Qu.:12.0 1st Qu.: 26.00 ## Median :15.0 Median : 36.00 ## Mean :15.4 Mean : 42.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is climate change real ?</title>
      <link>https://brendk.netlify.app/blogs/climate_change/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brendk.netlify.app/blogs/climate_change/</guid>
      <description>Following frequent claims from American politician that climate change was a hoax, we decided to do an unbiased investigation of this controversial topic.Records show that global temperature is rising at an alarming pace, but is it only a short-term phenomenon, or a lasting trend ?We will use our statistical tools and knowledge to assess global warming based on data published by NASA about the Combined Land-Surface Air and Sea-Surface Water Temperature Anomalies in the Northern Hemisphere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pay discrimination at Omega Group PLC</title>
      <link>https://brendk.netlify.app/blogs/omega/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brendk.netlify.app/blogs/omega/</guid>
      <description>Is there a significant difference between the salaries of men and women at Omega Group PLC ?Following the release of Omega Group PLC salary data, a quick analysis revealed that men executives salaries were USD 8’700 higher on average.
As it seems to be a considerable difference, we will investigate whether women executives are being discriminated in this company.
Shall we find a significant difference between the two groups, we will look at potential explanations to determine if other factors than gender can explain this difference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Physical activity benefits on US high schoolers health</title>
      <link>https://brendk.netlify.app/blogs/high_schoolers_health/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brendk.netlify.app/blogs/high_schoolers_health/</guid>
      <description>We will analyse the Youth Risk Behavior Surveillance System (YRBSS) survey, released every two years by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention conduct. This dataset contains several features about American high schoolers that will help us analyze health patterns.
First we have a look at the dataset to get a feel for missing values, summary statistics of numerical variables, and a very rough histogram.
data(yrbss)glimpse(yrbss)## Rows: 13,583## Columns: 13## $ age &amp;lt;int&amp;gt; 14, 14, 15, 15, 15, 15, 15, 14, 15, 15, 15.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>| How accurate is the Carhart four-factor model at explaining 
| securities returns in Covid-19 times ?
</title>
      <link>https://brendk.netlify.app/blogs/ff_carhart/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brendk.netlify.app/blogs/ff_carhart/</guid>
      <description>Executive SummaryThe goal of this project is to assess the ability of the Carhart 4 factor model in explaining stock returns. More precisely, we want to quantify the impact of Covid-19 on this accuracy.Are financial markets driven by factors during the pandemic ? What about previous crisis ?
The Carhart four-factor modelThe Carhart four-factor model is a multifactor model used to explain securities returns.It is an extension to the Fama-French three-factor model, designed by Eugene Fama and Keneth French in 1992, including an additional factor: the momentum.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>